<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questions>
    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>What are Rare Pepes and why should I care?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>Great question! In short, Rare Pepes are the first user generated NFTs. They were created on top of
                Bitcoin in the 2016 - 2017 period, using the <a href="http://counterparty.io/">Counterparty protocol</a>.
            </p>
            <p>To learn more about their history, check out this <a
                    href="https://app.pitch.com/app/public/player/d6eb5ef4-1084-418f-8760-1595dbaeea99">awesome
                presentation someone made</a>.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>What the heck is a dispenser?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>Dispensers are a magical Bitcoin smart contract that functions like a vending machine.</p>
            <p>The dispensers ask for a specific amount of BTC for each pepe they can dispense. If you send the amount
                asked for, it will dispense the pepe back to the address you sent from.
            </p>
            <p>You heard that right, the dispenser will send the pepe back to the address you sent the BTC from. This
                means that to receive your pepe you want to use a wallet that can see and access the pepe. Such as <a
                        href="http://RAREPEPEWALLET.com">RAREPEPEWALLET.com
                </a> or <a href="http://Freewallet.io">Freewallet.io</a>. Also known as a Counterparty enabled wallet.
            </p>
            <p>In cases where the vending machine has multiple units of a pepe, like PEPECASH, you can send the
                cumulative equivalent of the amount of PEPECASH you want.
            </p>
            <p>For example, if the PEPECASH is priced at 100 SATS, and you want two of them, you can send 200 SATS and
                you will get 2 PEPECASH. That is, of course. If the dispenser has 2 PEPECASH available. If you send more
                Bitcoin to a dispenser then it has available stock for, you will have to try and find the owner, not a
                trivial task. Kinda like trying to find the manager if a vending machine won't spit out your drink!
            </p>
            <p>In such cases you can go and try to find the owner of the dispenser on the <a
                    href="https://t.me/joinchat/QJdrG2ehHAfk5lKw">Rare Pepe telegram group
            </a> or ask for help there.
            </p>
            <p>It's also possible that someone sent BTC to a dispenser right before you do, and they get the dispenser
                first, emptying the stock available.
            </p>
            <p>To protect users from this problem, we link directly to Xchain, a more detailed block explorer that will
                warn you if the stock has been emptied. It also shows unconfirmed transactions that are incoming trying
                to take a part of the stock of that dispenser. <a
                        href="https://xchain.io/tx/ad9d5348b45f864cfbc4a9286e73f6a87101c4fb42ce5b86829c14c394f36469">
                    Here’s an example of an active dispenser.
                </a>
            </p>
            <p>We only display dispensers that are open at the time the page is loaded.</p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>Only send from XCP enabled Bitcoin wallets.</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>Rare pepes live on a Bitcoin sidechain called Counterparty (XCP). As such, pepes can live on any Bitcoin
                address, but only wallets that support the XCP protocol can show them to you and let you send them to
                other people or access their bonus content.
            </p>
            <p>When you send BTC to a dispenser, the dispenser automagically sends back the equivalent amount of pepes
                back to the address you sent to. If you send the BTC from an exchange or a non XCP enabled wallet then
                the pepe might be stuck there and it might not be easy to get it back.
            </p>
            <p>So, only use <a href="http://RAREPEPEWALLET.com">RAREPEPEWALLET.com</a> or <a
                    href="http://Freewallet.io">Freewallet.io
            </a> when you send BTC to Bitcoin dispensers. We do not recommend any other wallets.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>How do I create a dispenser?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>The best and recommended way to do it is with <a href="http://freewallet.io">Freewallet.io</a>’s Desktop
                version. You will need to have at least 0.5 XCP on the wallet and some BTC to pay for the transaction
                fees, as it all happens on top of Bitcoin rails.
            </p>
            <p>When you create a dispenser you are sending your Pepes to a distributed Counterparty escrow, a kind of
                smart contract. You are also giving it a receive address that should be different than the address you
                are sending the Pepe from. It is important that this address be new and not used regularly as any
                transactions that enter it could trigger the dispensers and send out Pepes.
            </p>
            <p>When you create a dispenser you choose how many units of a Pepe you want to dispenser and how much BTC
                has to be received per asset. You can buy multiples of an asset if the dispenser has stock available and
                if you send the equivalent amount of Bitcoin.
            </p>
            <p>The Dispenser looks at the receiving address and if it observers a BTC deposit to the receiving address
                then it dispenses a PEPE to the address that sent the Bitcoin automagically. This transfer does not take
                an extra Bitcoin transaction, it is settled on the Counterparty L2.
            </p>
            <p>Please note that Dispensers can not send money to Bitcoin addresses that start with a 3, only addresses
                that start with a 1 or a b. Aka Legacy or Segwit addresses, no p2sh or scripts.
            </p>
            <p>Also note that to cancel a dispenser you need to have the private key of the receiving address loaded up
                into a Counterparty compatible wallet.
            </p>
            <p>Last but not least, it is possible to put multiple dispensers on one address, but this is not recommended
                as it is off standard behaviour that might cause confusion for buyers and sellers. It is advised that
                every dispenser have a fresh Bitcoin address that is not reused or used for anything else.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>What is the XCP / PEPECASH DEX?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>XCP and PEPECASH are currency-like assets on top of the counterparty protocol. Counterparty is a side
                chain protocol on top of Bitcoin. This protocol supports a form of on-chain decentralized exchange that
                is trust minimized in nature. This means that there is no counter party, no custody risk, no third party
                middleman. You can trade your pepes with buyers directly.
            </p>
            <p>Sadly, because Counterparty is a kind of layer two protocol, it can not integrate Bitcoin directly into
                this DEX scheme. So only XCP and PEPECASH are really supported in this DEX format. However, Bitcoin
                dispensers are a functional alternative if you want to buy your Pepes with BTC which is much more liquid
                and easy to acquire than XCP or PEPECASH.
            </p>
            <p>One of the major benefits of the DEX is that you can place buy limit orders for a specific Pepe, and
                those orders will be visible to the market, letting you know where the active floor for a pepe might be.
                This is something currently not possible with Bitcoin dispensers.
            </p>
            <p>There are two recommended ways to access the Counterparty DEX. <a href="http://pepewallet.com/#">
                Rarepepewallet.com
            </a> (easier, less advanced features) and <a href="https://freewallet.io/">Freewallet.io</a> for Desktop
                (advanced features, harder to use).
            </p>
            <p>The easiest way to get PEPECASH or XCP is to buy them from dispensers with Bitcoin. Though you can also
                try to get them from an exchange.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>What does the “⚡” price mean?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>Rare Pepe World uses Bitcoin as the primary currency for pepes. This means that pepes costing tens of
                thousands of dollars or 0.50 cents worth of BTC all get denominated in Bitcoin.
            </p>
            <p>The problem of course, is the gigantic numbers! Look for example at GIVEKUDOS. It is worth (at the time of writing), more or less,
                0.50 cents worth of BTC. Which comes out to 0.00000750 BTC, or 750 Satoshis.
            </p>
            <p>Which one is prettier in this example? Well, of course, 750 Satoshis.</p>
            <p>In a case where the price of a pepe is above 1 million Satoshis, such as LordKeke which is a whopping
                2100 BTC(!), we would have to show it as 210,000,000,000 Satoshis! That doesn't make sense. So we show it
                as 2100 BTC instead!
            </p>
            <p>Does that make sense? Kind of how "Dollars" and "Cents" work. BTC and Satoshis are two ways of looking at
                the same monetary amount.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>Does this harm Bitcoin scaling?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>The Counterparty protocol has been around for a while and concerns about scaling have been with us as
                much as any other Bitcoin project. In fact, the fee prices post 2017 were a reason why the protocol kind
                of lost prominence. However, they continued to develop with scalability in mind.
            </p>
            <p>One of the key things about Counterparty transactions that has a big impact is that XCP assets are
                essentially transferred at a layer two protocol managed by counterparty, which stores some of the
                relevant bdata on the op-return area of Bitcoin transactions. This means that one transaction on the
                Bitcoin on chain layer can trigger multiple transfers on the XCP layer. This is particularly true with
                BTC denominated dispensers.
            </p>
            <p>Counterparty also has a protocol to send assets at scale, so that if you want to move a lot of NFTs for
                example from one address to another, this can be done more efficiently.
            </p>
            <p>Last but not least, there might be ways to move Counterparty assets to the Liquid Network if demand for
                such a thing arises. Currently many pepes cost hundreds of dollars or more, matching the high value use
                of Bitcoin as a settlement layer. If this gets priced out by onchain fees, there are options to
                potentially move assets to a higher layer, like Liquid. Currently however, fees are very affordable,
                especially compared to Ethereum or past eras of Bitcoin.
            </p>
            <p>Counterparty also supports Bech32 transactions and is positioned to benefit from the ongoing scalability
                developments made by Bitcoin core.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>

    <faq-item>
        <question>
            <div>How is real supply calculated?</div>
        </question>

        <answer>
            <p>The "Real Supply" shown throughout rare pepe world is a custom calculation we do in order to more
                accurately reflect the supply of pepes in the market.
            </p>
            <p>Where we differ from most other services in the space is that we take obvious burn addresses into account
                when counting the pepe supply and subtract assets on those addresses from the total supply.
            </p>
            <p>We also include asset destructions on top of the XCP protocol, unlike some sites.</p>
            <p>If you have created a new burn address and would like us to add it to our list to reflect updated
                balances, please email it to us at rarepepeworld@pm.me.
            </p>
            <p>Cheers!</p>
        </answer>
    </faq-item>
</questions>